<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <p>
    This page is intended for advanced users, those who maintain applications which embed
    or extend NetLogo, or those who maintain large numbers of models and want to be
    more familiar with the format they are saved in.
    For most users, the saving, loading, and editing features NetLogo provides will
    be more than sufficient to serve their needs.
  </p>
  <p>
    The schema for the <span class="mono">nlogox</span> format is built using
    <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML_Schema_(W3C)">W3C XML Schema</a> (sometimes referred to as
    <span class="mono">xsd</span>), a standard format for describing xml-based
    data representations. <span class="mono">nlogox</span> files are also valid XML files
    and may be operated on using XML tools such as XSLT and XPath.
    The NetLogo model schema is included with the HTML version of this manual <a href="model.xsd">here</a>.
    To view the schema, save the linked page and open in a text editor.
  </p>
  <p>
    There are several major areas that this guide covers. Many users are only interested
    in a single type or section of the format; we recommend using the Table of Contents
    (below) to learn more about your area of interest.
    This page is divided into several topics.
    The first of these is <a href="#file-sections">File Sections</a> which describes the
    elements which live directly inside the <code><![CDATA[<model>]]></code> tag.
      The second major area, <a href="#composite-types">Composite Types</a> covers the
      attributes and sub-elements of various xml elements used in the file.
      Most of the sections define their content in terms of these types and provide links
      where appropriate.
      The final major areas are <a href="#atomic-types">Atomic Types</a> which gives
      information about the syntax and meaning of various format and attribute content,
      and <a href="#enumerations">Enumerations</a> which provides a list of special values
      used in various places in the file format.
    </p>
  </div>

